Preliminary Guide to the Richard Irvin & Co. Records circa 1824-1939 (bulk, 1860s-1919) MS 324
New-York Historical Society
Richard Irvin & Co. records
circa 1824-1939 (bulk, 1860s-1919)
New-York Historical Society
Richard Irvin & Co.
MS 324
approximately 138 Linear feet in 10 document boxes (7 full and 3 half-size), 88 record cartons, and 394 volumes.
Business records of New York City commission merchants and bankers Richard Irvin & Co., headed by Scottish immigrant Richard Irvin (1799–1888), his son, Richard Irvin Jr. (1840–1896), and grandson, Richard Irvin III (1869–1938), between about 1824 and 1939. Richard Irvin & Co. was the sole New York consignee of Gartsherrie Iron supplied by William Baird & Co. of Glasgow, and agents for the Great Western Steamship Company, which instituted the first regular transatlantic steamer service in 1838–1846. Among the collection is evidence of the firm's extensive business with Gibbs, Bright & Co. of Liverpool, and with Samuel Irvin & Co. of Glasgow; their exports to Bright Bros. & Co. of Melbourne and Sydney, Australia; their trade with Nova Scotia and New Brunswick, Canada; their activities as New York agents for Satterthwaite & Co., stock and share brokers of London; their exclusive foreign representation of the Maxwell automobile; their brokerage of the guano and nitrate trade between England and South America; and their interest in the manufacture of pneumatic cushions and mattresses, and railway cars for export to Santo Domingo.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers, who should be aware that the collection is not processed. Materials remain largely in the condition in which they arrived at the New-York Historical Society in 1945 and 1950, namely, in countless tied bundles of bills, receipts, insurance policies, and trifold correspondence. Many of the 394 volumes, which were shrinkwrapped in 2019-2020 for off-site storage, lack dates or identifying information on their exteriors.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Misses Frances Irvin and Clara Irvin, 1945 and 1950.
The donors were the granddaughters of Richard Irvin (1799–1888) and sisters of Richard Irvin III (1869–1938). For details of their gift, see Annual Report of The New-York Historical Society for the Year 1945, 18, 32-33, 45; The New-York Historical Society Quarterly vol. 30, no. 1 (January 1946), 60; and Annual Report of The New-York Historical Society for the Year 1950, 55.)
Arrangement
The collection is organized by format in two series:
Series I.
Files, circa 1843-1919
Series II.
Bound volumes, circa 1848-1914
Historical note
Glasgow native Richard Irvin (1799–1888), son of William and Janet (Scott) Irvin, left Scotland in 1824 to join the shipping business his uncle, Thomas Irvin, had established in New York in 1787. At the death of Thomas in 1836, Richard assumed control, and brought two of his sons—Alexander P. and Richard Irvin Jr.—into the firm. About 1840 they became the sole New York consignees of the Gartsherrie Iron supplied by William Baird & Co. of Glasgow, one of the United Kingdom's largest iron dealers. They were also New York agents for the Great Western Steamship Company, which instituted the first regular transatlantic steamer service via the vessels SS Great Western and SS Great Britain in 1838–1846.
By 1863 the firm—then known as Richard Irvin & Co.—had expanded from its original commission business to banking. Richard Irvin served as a director of the Mechanics' National Bank for fifty years, and was the oldest member of the New York Chamber of Commerce (having joined in 1834) when he died in 1888.
Son Richard Irvin Jr. (1840–1896), who carried on the business after his father's death, had philanthropic and cultural interests. He provided financial support to numerous organizations, among them the Bach Singers of New York, the Cantata Club, and the American School of Opera.
At Richard Irvin Jr.'s death, the firm was revived by his nephew, Richard Irvin III (1869–1938). A banker like his uncle and grandfather, Richard III was one of the organizers and a former treasurer of the Maxwell-Briscoe Motor Company, an early manufacturer of automobiles. Richard Irvin & Co. folded with his death. Richard's surviving sisters, Frances and Clara, donated the firm's business records to the New-York Historical Society in 1945.
[This note draws on Richard Irvin Sr.'s Wikipedia entry, his obituary from The New York Times (June 29, 1888), and the Times obituaries of Richard Irvin Jr. (March 9, 1896, p. 5) and Richard Irvin III (May 25, 1938, p. 23). See also William M. MacBean, Biographical Register of Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York (Printed for the Society, 1925), vol. 2, p. 98, entry 920, "Richard Irvin," and Arthur J. Breton, A Guide to the Manuscript Collections of The New-York Historical Society (Westport, Conn.: Greenwood Press, Inc., 1972), vol. 1, p. 465, entry 2857, "Richard Irvin & Co."]
Related Materials
Richard Irvin (1799-1888) served as president of Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York in 1842-1851 and 1862-1864. The Saint Andrew's Society, formed in 1756, is a fraternal and charitable organization whose members claim Scottish ancestry. See the New-York Historical Society's Guide to the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York Records, 1785-2014 (MS 2997).
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the business records of Richard Irvin & Co., commission merchants and bankers of New York City, and spans the years 1824 through 1939, with the bulk of items appearing to cover the 1860s through about 1919. Descriptions of the collection made when it came to the New-York Historical Society (in two or possibly three accessions) and subsequent surveys suggest its outside date range of 1824–1939. But while the records might extend as far back as 1824, and into the late 1930s, the unprocessed state of the collection, particularly the bound volumes in Series II, makes it impossible to ascertain truly accurate dates. The earliest items observed while rehousing the collection dated from circa 1839; the latest, from circa 1919.
The collection includes letters received, letterpress copies of letters sent, account books of various kinds, insurance policies, bills of lading, gold checks, bills of exchange, receipts, invoices, etc. A sampling of the papers reveals: the firm's activities as agents for the sale of Gartsherrie and other iron and steel from England; their extensive business with Gibbs, Bright & Co. of Liverpool, and with Samuel Irvin & Co. of Glasgow; extensive exports to Bright Bros. & Co. of Melbourne and Sydney, Australia; trade with Nova Scotia and New Brunswick, Canada; their activities as New York agents for Satterthwaite & Co., stock and share brokers of London; as exclusive foreign representatives of the Maxwell automobile; agents of National Steel Co.; sole manufacturers of pneumatic cushions and mattresses; agents in the guano and nitrate trade between England and Peru, Chile, and Bolivia; agents for the sale of railway cars, particularly to the Samana & Santiago Railway Co., Santo Domingo; exporters to New Zealand; agents for Niagara Emery Mills, Inc., Lockport, New York; extensive transactions in stocks, bonds, and gold; etc.
[This note draws on Arthur J. Breton, A Guide to the Manuscript Collections of The New-York Historical Society (Westport, Conn.: Greenwood Press, Inc., 1972), vol. 1, 465, entry 2857.]
Account books.; Bills of exchange.; Bills of lading.; Bonds (negotiable instruments).; Business records.; Checks (bank checks); Commercial correspondence.; Insurance policies.; Invoices.; Ledgers (account books).; Letter books.; Letterpress copybooks.; Orders to pay.; Receipts (financial records).; Stock certificates.; Vouchers.; Banks and banking -- New York (State) -- New York.; Commission merchants; Guano; Iron industry and trade; Nitrate industry; Railroads.; Scottish Americans -- New York (State).; Shipping -- New York (State) -- New York.; Steel industry and trade; Irvin, Richard, 1799-1888 (Merchant); Irvin, Richard, Jr., 1840-1896; Irvin, Richard, III, 1869-1938; Bright Bros. & Co.; Gibbs, Bright & Co.; Maxwell-Briscoe Motor Company; Richard Irvin & Co. -- Archives; Samuel Irvin & Co.; Satterthwaite & Co.
- Series I. Files, circa 1843-1919
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains the day-to-day business records of Richard Irvin & Co., commission merchants and bankers of New York, spanning from about 1843 through 1919, but possibly dating from as early as 1824 and as late as 1939 (the 1824–1939 range is based on existing descriptions, but no materials from those outside years were observed while surveying the collection). Formats include bills of exchange, bills of lading (inward and outward), bonds, checks, commercial correspondence, insurance policies, invoices, orders to pay, receipts, stock certificates, and vouchers. The papers reveal the firm's myriad activities: as agents for the sale of iron and steel from England; their exporting and importing business with companies in Australia and Canada; their role as New York agents for Satterthwaite & Co., stock and share brokers of London; and as exclusive foreign representatives of the Maxwell-Briscoe Motor Company, early manufacturers of automobiles. Richard Irvin & Co. also had a hand in the manufacture of pneumatic cushions and mattresses, the construction and sale of railway cars, and the trade of guano and nitrate between England, Peru, Chile, and Bolivia. The container list records what information could be gleaned from the collection's sparsely identified bundles.
  Arrangement
  The material in boxes 1–34 appears to have been processed in late 1945 by a New York University intern (or a successor) engaged to organize the collection shortly after its accession (see her notes in Box 98). In 2019–2020, to prepare the collection for shipment to off-site storage, New-York Historical Society archivists transferred the material from boxes 11–33 to record cartons. They also transferred the contents of fifteen unwieldy wooden trunks to record cartons (boxes 35–98) while attempting to group their contents by type, e.g., correspondence, checks, insurance policies, bills of lading, statements of exchange, etc. Most material remains tied in trifold bundles and packets. Note that the trunk numbering mentioned in the container list was assigned by New-York Historical Society staff, and simply reflects the haphazard order in which the trunks were stacked; it has no bearing on the chronology of their contents. Similarly, the labeling and dates on the outside of most trunks bore little relation to what was inside, but has nevertheless been transcribed to preserve any possible historical significance.
  - Maxwell-Briscoe Motor Co., 1906 (Offsite-box 1)
  - Maxwell-Briscoe Motor Co., 1905-1910 (Offsite-box 2)
  - Bach Singers of New York, 1900 (Offsite-box 3)
  - Adamite Abrasive Co., 1911-1914 (Offsite-box 4)
  - Brisco [Briscoe?] Manufacturing Co., Marion Manufacturing Co., 1902-1907 (Offsite-box 5)
  - Maxwell-Briscoe Motor Co., 1904-1907 (Offsite-box 6)
  - Muldoon Underwear Co., 1910-1911 (Offsite-box 7)
  - India Rubber & Gutta Percha Insulating Co., 1883-1890 (Offsite-box 8)
  - India Rubber & Gutta Percha Insulating Co., 1888-1889 (Offsite-box 9)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-I, 1867 (Offsite-box 10)
  - Incoming correspondence, J-Z, 1867 (Offsite-box 11)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-K, 1868 (Offsite-box 12)
  - Incoming correspondence, L-Y, 1868 (Offsite-box 13)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-M, 1869 (Offsite-box 14)
  - Incoming correspondence, M-Z, 1869 (Offsite-box 15)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-L, 1870 (Offsite-box 16)
  - Incoming correspondence, M-Z, 1870 (Offsite-box 17)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-M, 1871 (Offsite-box 18)
  - Incoming correspondence, L-W, 1871 (Offsite-box 19)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-G, 1872 (Offsite-box 20)
  - Incoming correspondence, I-J, 1872, and early firm papers, 1839-1872 (Offsite-box 21)
  - Incoming correspondence, K-Z, 1872 (Offsite-box 22)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-J, 1873 (Offsite-box 23)
  - Incoming correspondence, N-Z, 1873 (Offsite-box 24)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-R, 1874 (Offsite-box 25)
  - Incoming correspondence, 1875 (Offsite-box 26)
  - Incoming correspondence, S. Irvin-W, 1875 (Offsite-box 27)
  - Letters, memos, case paperwork, 1868-1889 (Offsite-box 28)
  - Case paperwork, 1870-1895 (Offsite-box 29)
  - Insurance policies and various annual reports, 1846-1885 (Offsite-box 30)
  - Irvin & Co. and predecessors, 1800-1894 (Offsite-box 31)
  - Bills of lading (inward/outward), correspondence, 1867-1911 (Offsite-box 32)
  - Case paperwork, 1872-1886 (Offsite-box 33)
  - Miscellaneous, 1858-1887 (Offsite-box 34)
  - Contents of trunk 1 [marked "Blue 1864"]
    - Mining companies' reports and correspondence, 1902-1906 (Offsite-box 35)
      Correspondence between Irvin and various mining companies, including American Quartz Mining Co. and Crosby Mine, as well as annual reports and other papers.
    - Card catalog for correspondence, 1909 (Offsite-box 36)
      Index cards containing names, addresses, and lists of what appears to be outgoing correspondence and dates sent.
    - Checks, correspondence, bond and investment lists, newspaper clippings, and railroad companies' annual reports (Offsite-box 37)
    - Bills, accounts, receipts, and pamphlets (Offsite-box 38)
  - Contents of trunk 2 [marked "1849-1850; '84, '85, some odds"]
    - Correspondence (bills), A-F, 1884-1885 (Offsite-box 39)
    - Correspondence (bills), G-L, 1884-1885 (Offsite-box 40)
    - Correspondence (bills), M-R, 1864-1890; 1884-1885 (Offsite-box 41)
    - Correspondence (bills), S-Y, 1865-1895; 1884-1885 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Bills, checks/vouchers, bills of lading, drafts paid, exchanges, 1884-1893 (Offsite-box 43)
    - Accounts, bond papers, Australian orders, land and railroad companies, 1884-1890 (Offsite-box 44)
  - Contents of trunk 3 [marked "1873-(1874? '75?)]
    - Bank vouchers, bonds, receipts, bills, miscellaneous correspondence and documents, 1890-1893 (Offsite-box 45)
      Various financial records as well as papers on Irvin's brother's death.
    - Correspondence (bills), A-H, 1890-1893 (Offsite-box 46)
    - Correspondence (bills), I-Q, 1890-1893 (Offsite-box 47)
    - Correspondence (bills), R-W, 1890-1893 (Offsite-box 48)
    - Various estates, bills for exchange, drafts, receipts, and wills (Offsite-box 49)
      Papers on various estates including the Cole estate, Robertson farm, Thomas estate, and William Bruce estate.
  - Contents of trunk 4 [marked "1854-1855"]
    - Thirds of exchanges, drafts paid, coupons, duplicate invoices, 1844-1875 (Offsite-box 50)
    - Exchanges bought, drawn, 1864-1868 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Thirds of exchanges, other documents, 1870-1875 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Correspondence (duplicates), some miscellaneous, 1868-1874 (Offsite-box 53)
    - Exchanges drawn and sold, vouchers, receipts, stamps, bills, 1866-1875 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Checks/vouchers, gold checks, 1864-1875 (Offsite-box 55)
  - Contents of trunk 5 [marked "1856-1857"]
    - Correspondence, drafts paid, miscellaneous papers, 1870-1900 (Offsite-box 56)
    - Sales and purchase notes, claims paid, receipts, and checks, 1864-1871 (Offsite-box 57)
    - Melbourne: accounts, sales, remittances, settled accounts, protested bills, 1867-1871 (Offsite-box 58)
    - Exchanges, storage receipts, notes, 1868-1878 (Offsite-box 59)
    - Bills, thirds of receipts, miscellaneous papers, 1867-1875 (Offsite-box 60)
  - Contents of trunk 6 [marked "1863"]
    - Powers of attorney, settled accounts, coupons, bonds, miscellaneous papers, 1859-1902 (Offsite-box 61)
    - Assorted accounts papers, 1861-1878 (Offsite-box 62)
      Papers regarding Irvin's accounts with companies including Western Bank of Scotland, Fish and Lee, Buckeye Engine Company, Climax Refining Company, and others.
  - Contents of trunk 7 [marked "1886-1887"]
    - Correspondence (bills), A-F, 1886-1887 (Offsite-box 63)
    - Correspondence (bills), G-M, 1886-1887 (Offsite-box 64)
    - Correspondence (bills), N-W, 1886-1887 (Offsite-box 65)
    - Annual reports, railroad companies' papers, receipts, invoices, checks, circa 1843-1884 (Offsite-box 66)
    - Checks, receipts, invoices, bills, circa 1872-1885 (Offsite-box 67)
  - Contents of trunk 8 [marked "1880-1881"]
    - Correspondence (bills), A-F, 1880-1882, 1890-1891 (Offsite-box 68)
    - Correspondence (bills) G-O, 1880-1882, 1890 (Offsite-box 69)
    - Correspondence (bills), P-Y, 1880-1881, 1891 (Offsite-box 70)
    - Bank vouchers, insurance policies, letters and receipts, miscellaneous, 1880-1881 (Offsite-box 71)
    - Bills, exchanges, bills of lading, 1880-1881, 1890 (Offsite-box 72)
  - Contents of trunk 9 [marked "1884-1885"]
    - Correspondence (bills), B, 1892 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), D, 1892 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), E, 1892-1894 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), G, 1879, 1885 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), I, 1895 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), K, 1892, 1894 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), L, 1884, 1893-1894 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), M, 1885, 1892 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), N, 1890, 1893, 1895 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), P, 1894-1896 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), R, 1893 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), S, 1884-1885, 1893 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), T, 1883-1885 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), V, 1893 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), W, 1892, 1895 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Correspondence (bills), Y, 1891 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Letterpress copybook, 1860-1861 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Balance sheet, 1866-1867 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Petty cash statements, 1866-1870 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Sales closed, 1869 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Miscellaneous, 1860s-1890s (Offsite-box 74)
    - Protested bills, etc., settled, 1870 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Sale & purchase notes, 1870 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Notes payable at office, 1870, 1872 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Stocks, bonds, vouchers (various), circa 1870-1896 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Insurance policies, etc., circa 1876-1891 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Drafts paid, 1882-1884 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Bonds & Stocks Purchased & Sold, 1884-1885 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Seconds of Exchange, 1892-1894 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Cantata Club, 1896-1898 (Offsite-box 74)
  - Contents of trunk 10 [marked "1872-1873"]
    - Racine & Min(?) R.R. Bonds, Trustees' Receipts, 1866-1867 February 2 (Offsite-box 75)
    - Fairchild Iron Co., stock ledger, 1870-1875 (Offsite-box 75)
    - Account book: Newport House; 31 Washington Square; 176 Elizabeth Street; Potter Barques "Monitor & Ironsides", 1876-1878 (Offsite-box 75)
    - National Mechanics' Bank checkbook, 1884 February 6 - November 7 (Offsite-box 75)
    - John D. Prinse(?) Estate, 1884 July 15 - 1886 June 9 (Offsite-box 75)
    - Account book: "Robert, May, John, Ethel" [Irvin], 1884-1886 (Offsite-box 75)
    - Cole Estate checkbook, 1884-1891 (Offsite-box 75)
    - Mechanics' National Bank: Richard Irvin bankbooks, 1890-1893 (Offsite-box 75)
    - Alexander P. Irvin, Robt. L. Taylor, undated (Offsite-box 75)
    - G. G. Gray Estate, undated (Offsite-box 75)
    - Memo books: Richard Irvin (small bundle), undated (Offsite-box 75)
    - Annual reports, brochures, prospectuses, etc., for mining, railroad, and investment companies, and charitable institutions, circa 1869-1901 (Offsite-box 76)
    - Bills, letters, estate papers, etc., some marked "found in Richard Irvin's desk", 1860s-1880s? (Offsite-box 77)
    - Bills, letters, estate papers, etc., some marked "found in Richard Irvin's desk", 1860s-1880s? (Offsite-box 78)
  - Contents of trunk 11 [marked "1878-1879"]
    - Correspondence (bills), A-F, 1877 (Offsite-box 79)
    - Correspondence (bills), H-I, 1877 (Offsite-box 79)
    - Correspondence (bills), L, 1877 (Offsite-box 79)
    - Correspondence (bills), M, 1876-1877 (Offsite-box 79)
    - Correspondence (bills), N-P, 1875, 1877 (Offsite-box 79)
    - Correspondence (bills), R, 1876 (Offsite-box 79)
    - Correspondence (bills), S-T, 1877 (Offsite-box 79)
    - Correspondence (bills), W, 1877 (Offsite-box 79)
    - Correspondence (bills), miscellaneous, 1877 (Offsite-box 79)
    - Correspondence (bills), A-P, 1878 (Offsite-box 80)
    - Correspondence (bills), R-W, 1878 (Offsite-box 80)
    - Correspondence (bills), A-P, 1879 (Offsite-box 81)
    - Correspondence (bills), R-T, 1879 (Offsite-box 81)
    - Correspondence (bills), V, W, Y, 1879 (Offsite-box 81)
    - Mechanics' National Bank: Currency checks, 1877-1879 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Mechanics' National Bank: Gold, 1877-1878 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Bills of lading, outward, 1876-1879 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Bills of lading, inward, 1878-1879 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Orders, 1877-1879 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Exchange drawn, 1877-1879 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Exchange bought, 1877-1879 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Registered letter receipts, 1877-1879 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Drafts paid, 1877, 1879-1880 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Thirds of Exchange, 1878-1879 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Account book: "Tobacco / Strips", 1877-1880 (Offsite-box 83)
    - Miscellaneous acceptances, bills, correspondence, vouchers, etc., circa 1876-1880 (Offsite-box 83)
    - Muldoon Underwear Co. receipt pads (9 copies), circa 1910-1919 (Offsite-box 83)
  - Contents of trunk 12 [marked "1869"]
    - Correspondence (bills), B-D, 1876 (Offsite-box 84)
    - Correspondence (bills), F-J, 1876 (Offsite-box 84)
    - Correspondence (bills), L-P, 1876 (Offsite-box 84)
    - Correspondence (bills), S-T, 1876 (Offsite-box 84)
    - Correspondence (bills), V-W, Y, 1876 (Offsite-box 84)
    - Correspondence (bills), B, G, 1877 (Offsite-box 85)
    - Correspondence (bills), I-K, 1877 (Offsite-box 85)
    - Correspondence (bills), R-S, 1877 (Offsite-box 85)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, bills, receipts, stocks, etc., 1870s-1880s? (Offsite-box 85)
    - Lackawana Rail Road Company bonds, 1866? (Offsite-box 86)
    - Annual reports, etc., circa 1869-1892 (Offsite-box 86)
    - Miscellaneous bills, legal papers, mortgages, stocks, etc., 1870s (Offsite-box 86)
    - Racine & Mississippi R.R. litigation & etc., undated (Offsite-box 86)
    - Montana Iron Company R.R. Iron (claims? court case?), 1857-1858 (Offsite-box 87)
    - Fairchance Iron Co. letters and account book, 1870s (Offsite-box 87)
    - Exchange, bought, 1872 (Offsite-box 87)
    - Mechanics' National Bank. Gold checks, 1874-1876 (Offsite-box 87)
    - Mechanics' National Bank. Checks, 1876 (Offsite-box 87)
    - Drafts paid, 1876 (Offsite-box 87)
    - Thirds of Exchange, 1877 (Offsite-box 87)
    - Papers in re: Old claims, loans, etc., settled & unsettled, 1880s-1890s (Offsite-box 87)
    - Checks, miscellaneous, 1890s (Offsite-box 87)
    - Richard Irvin Sr. private letters, 1896 May (Offsite-box 87)
    - International R.R. of Texas, undated (Offsite-box 87)
    - Litchfield suit, undated (Offsite-box 87)
    - N.Y. Common Pleas. In the matter of the assignments of Robert L. Taylor. Report & Opinion, undated (Offsite-box 87)
    - State of Georgia papers, undated (Offsite-box 87)
  - Contents of trunk 13 [marked "1888-1889"]
    - Correspondence (bills), B, J, U, V, 1887 (Offsite-box 88)
    - Correspondence (bills), A-O, 1888 (Offsite-box 88)
    - Correspondence (bills), R-U, W, 1888 (Offsite-box 88)
    - Correspondence (bills), A-H, 1889 (Offsite-box 89)
    - Correspondence (bills), J-N, P, 1889 (Offsite-box 89)
    - Correspondence (bills), R-T, 1889 (Offsite-box 89)
    - Correspondence (bills), V-W, Y, 1889 (Offsite-box 89)
    - Insurance policies, expired, 1880 (Offsite-box 90)